All right. In the last video, we talked
about how to use this substring um
function. So, what I'm going to do is
I'm going to show you how to use a
related function called substr. So,
substring, if you recall, it took a
starting position and an ending
position. So, if we wanted to get Bruce,
then we'd have to say start at position
zero and end at position five. Um, if we
wanted to get Wayne, then we'd have to
say start at position six and end at
position uh 7 8 9 10 11. End at position
11. And that can be kind of a pain to
grab something out of the middle using
substring. So, I'm going to show you a
different function that'll allow you to
do something similar. So, if we do my
texts substr,
we can say we want to grab Wayne out of
this um sentence. So, what we're going
to do is we're going to start at
position 0 1 2 3 4 5 6. The W is in
position 6 and then a comma and then how
long is Wayne. So, it says the number of
characters to include. So, rather than
having to figure out where Wayne ends,
we can just say Wayne is 1 2 3 4 5
letters. So, we can put a five here. We
put a semicolon and we save that. And we
come over and we reload our page.
We now get the text Wayne. So, we didn't
have to figure out
the ending portion of Wayne. We didn't
have to figure out what character
position this is. We could just say
Wayne is five letters long. So, start at
the sixth position in the sentence where
the W is and go five characters. And so,
if you're just trying to find text in
the middle of the string, substr is
helpful.